<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ian's Mutterings.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/</link><description>Ian's Ramblings.</description><atom:link href="https://ianbarton.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:ian@ianbarton.net"&gt;Ian Barton.&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 10:27:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Poundland Christmas lights Mods.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Plus how to make them run from a usb charger instead of batteries. You need a
couple of 10 ohm resistors and a soldering iron. I am definitely going to try
this. One of those "I did it because I could" projects.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="" height="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_ds5XFJvPs?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:44:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Free Photos</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
When we went to see our eldest daughter at Uni last weekend I noticed that she
had lots of postcard-sized photos on her noticeboard. Prints are "Free" up to
45 6x4 per month, or a total of 500 per year. Other sizes are available if you
pay. There is a delivery charge of £3.99 (ie not totally free), but it seems
reasonable for what you get. You can print directly from Google photos, or
photos on your phone. Quality looked OK to me, but I am not a pixel peeper.
&lt;a href="http://www.freeprints.co.uk"&gt;http://www.freeprints.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brother P Labeller</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have had a Brother P Touch label printer for years. I don't think that they
sell my model any longer and I expect you can find a cheaper equivalent to this
one. It's very simple to use and has a built-in cutter and gizmo to separate
the label from the backing tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I use it for labeling all sorts of things, such as files and storage
boxes. It's great for labeling wall warts. Most of us have drawers full of
rechargeable electronic items, which come with their own wall wart. If you
don't label the plug it can be almost impossible to work out which plug you
should use to power/recharge a particular bit of electronics.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2Cf2IuE"&gt;Amazon link.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:09:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Service Charges in Restaurants</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Service Charges in Restaurants.  If I go to a restaurant, rather than a self
service cafe, I can't avoid "Service". It's a non optional part of the
experience. As such the price should be built into the price of the meal. If I
get crap service, I simply won't go back to the same place again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don't think any other part of the economy has such a strange idea of selling
you something that includes a service element. If I take my car into the garage
I don't expect to pay an extra 10% because the mechanic did their job properly.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:08:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Duronic Electric Hub</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-duronic-electric-hub/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/duronic_hob.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Thermos"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/duronic_hob.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A recent problem with our Aga means that we are without heating in the kitchen,
clothes dryer, hot water and the ability to cook anything except by using the
microwave. It will probably be out of action for a week or so while I run some
new copper pipe and move the control box.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Duronic Electric Hob has two different sized rings and seems reliable so
far. It's easy to clean and powerful enough to heat things rapidly. I think
it's pasta with everything until the Aga is fixed:)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2ABA5rz"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-duronic-electric-hub/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:06:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Citibikes Vienna</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-citibikes-vienna/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
A few years ago I tried to hire a couple of Boris Bikes in London with my
son. Despite help from an Official Assistant, we were unable to unlock two
bikes at once. So Boris you owe me £15, which with late payment charges and
interest comes to just over £10,000.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Citibikes in Vienna is much better! There are various apps which show you the
location of all the docking stations and the number of bikes available at each
one. You can do most of the preliminary registration stuff on the
website. However, the final step of registering your debit card requires you to
use one of the card readers at a bike station. Note for Monzo users, just tell
the machine it's a credit card when registering.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fees are very reasonable. The first hour is free and the second costs
1EU. Vienna is pancake flat with lots of cycle lanes, so even occasional
cyclists should be fine cycling around easy and safe.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
However, the bikes are really heavy. They would probably survive a direct hit
from an anti-tank missile. There is a single front brake, but the main braking
is activated by back pedaling. If you are used to aligning your pedals when you
mount the bike by sticking your foot under a pedal and back pedalling to get
the pedal in the correct position, you can't do this on a Citibike.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are three gears. However, the weight of the bike means that even on
slight inclines you have to push hard in the lowest gear.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are a regular cyclist you will find the weight and braking system very
annoying. On my 6.5k ride I averaged about 16kph. On a similar route with my
normal road bike this would have been about 35kph.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In conclusion good bike for short rides (10-15 minutes) at a very reasonable
price.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.citybikewien.at/en/"&gt;https://www.citybikewien.at/en/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-citibikes-vienna/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:05:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Self Assembly Flat Pack Furniture</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-self-assembly-flat-pack-furniture/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Self Assembly Furniture.  +Ted Salmon You need to hire my 17 year old
daughter:) She is an absolute wizard. Wardrobes, desks, cupboards, etc. Give
her a few tools and come back in a couple of hours to view the finished
product. For some weird reason she enjoys doing it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-self-assembly-flat-pack-furniture/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:03:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lint and Fluff Roller.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-lint-and-fluff-roller/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/lint_roller.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Thermos"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/lint_roller.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In a house full of cats and a dog, clothes quickly get covered with various cat
and dog hairs. Lazy people like me just ignore them. However, the female
members of the household are much fussier :) These lint rollers are very
effective at getting off animal hairs from your clothes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
They come with a roll of "sticky tape" in perforated sections. You tear off a
section and wrap it around the roller. The run the roller over your clothes and
the hairs will automagically stick to it. If you stick a plastic bag over the
roller when you have finished, you can get multiple uses from each sticky tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2TA3No6"&gt;
Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-lint-and-fluff-roller/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:02:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ruffwear Dog Harness</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-ruffwear-dog-harness/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/dog_harness.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Thermos"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/dog_harness.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have tried several different harnesses for our dog. This is the best we have
found. It's easy to adjust and put on. There are two attachment points for the
lead, so you can choose a position that suits your dog. It's a close fit, so
your dog can squeeze under gates, or dive through hedges without getting
stuck. There is a small ID pocket, where you can put the dog's tag, with
his/her name and your phone number. The adjustability makes it unlikely it will
chafe your dog.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ruffwear makes a variety of "Dog wear". I want to get him a set of panniers, so
he can carry his own food on camping trips!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2Tyt9CB"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-ruffwear-dog-harness/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:00:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bamboo Sheets</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-bamboo-sheets/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
As someone who can sleep almost anywhere and if the sheets are uncomfortable,
I'll just sleep on the floor or on top of the bed, I was deeply skeptical about
bamboo sheets. I thought bamboo, was only used for the sticks that hold up your
peas and beans:)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have to admit that I was completely wrong to be so skeptical. They are very
comfortable, feeling much cooler than cotton in summer. Also,they feel much
"smoother" than cotton.
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B01I59UTDA/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1"&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B01I59UTDA/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2H7ZkYq"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-bamboo-sheets/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 11:59:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>