<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ian's Tech Ramblings.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/</link><description>Ian's Tech Ramblings.</description><atom:link href="https://ianbarton.net/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:ian@ianbarton.net"&gt;Ian Barton.&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 13:12:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>SJ Cam 8 Pro Review.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-04-24-sjcam-8-pro-review/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
In my search for a new action camera I decided to buy the SJ Cam 8 Pro from
Amazon. The specifications looked good including optical image stabilization
and better battery life than its competitors. However, on the three cameras I
received from Amazon, the front display never worked on two and on the third it
failed after a couple of days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have heard that there have been problems with copies of the SJ Cam being
distributed. I have no idea if the three cameras I received were illegal copies
or not. The packaging and included accessories appeared to be genuine. Whatever
the reason, the three cameras I received were unreliable, so I decide not to
buy a camera made by SJ Cam again.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-04-24-sjcam-8-pro-review/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 16:42:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefly 8SE Action Camera.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-03-29-firefly-8SE-action-camera/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I am a keen cyclist who rides mainly on country lanes. However, I do cycle
through some of the local small towns. Most of the motorists are considerate
and I usually get a cheery wave when I pull over to let them past on single
track roads. Unfortunately, there are an increasing number of
inconsiderate/incompetent motorists. In the last couple of weeks I have had a
couple of very close shaves, which would have resulted in serious injury if I
had been hit. So I decided to get some sort of action camera to record my
rides. This won't prevent me from being injured, but at least I will have some
sort of record of what happened. Also I can gather evidence of the small
proportion of drivers who think passing you a few inches away at 60mph is good
driving.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have got an old GoPro Hero3, which is a decent enough camera. However,
battery life is very short at around 1hr and it can't be charged while in
use. Also it doesn't have any image stabilization, so on our potholed roads
it records very shaky footage. After doing some searching and looking at lots
of YouTube reviews I decided to buy the Firefly 8SE. The Firefly has a couple
of features that I required:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be used while recharging the battery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optical image stabilization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I bought my camera from Amazon, although you can buy it direct slightly cheaper
from places like Gearbest. The box contains a waterproof case
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microphone. Package includes a separate usb microphone (there is an internal
one too).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery life at around 100 minutes at 1080P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be used whilst it is being recharged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be set to record videos in short segments. If the memory card fills up,
the oldest clips will be deleted. So, it can be used as a dashcam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of clips, buckles and mounts included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can record in 4k&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software image stabilization at 1080P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor niggle: recharging is via mini USB (presumably to be compatible with GoPro)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDMI output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various modes: car mode, timelapse, can save photos in RAW.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The camera can't be recharged while it is in the waterproof case. New cases are
inexpensive, so I intend to cut a small slot in the case so I can plug in the
USB cable to recharge while riding. In anything except torrential rain this
should be adequately water resistant.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The image stabilization worked very well on our roads. Footage taken when the
handlebars were juddering over badly surface road looked quite stable on the
video. Most important I could easily read the number plates on passing cars.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Some more minor niggles:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Touch screen can require a few prods to work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some button actions not very intuitive: you have to work out which of the
small buttons on the side you need to long press for 3 seconds to toggle the wifi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the included mounts and brackets are a bit fragile. You probably need
to buy some decent ones if you use them on a regular basis. I snapped one
bracket the second time I used it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people complain about whining on the audio when the screen is turned
on. I haven't noticed this, but I don't really need to record audio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2CM9sBe"&gt;https://amzn.to/2CM9sBe&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-03-29-firefly-8SE-action-camera/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:59:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon Smart Plugs.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-03-10-amazon-smart-plugs/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/amazon_smart_plug.jpg" class="rounded
float-left" alt="Amazon smart plug"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/amazon_smart_plug.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have had a couple of Echo Dots and an Echo speaker for a couple of
years. However, we don't have any "Smart gadgets". Something to turn off the
lights would be useful, as other family members think that lights have an "On"
switch, but it has no "Off" function. However, all our switches are brass and
most of the bulbs are candles, for which there don't seem to be any aesthetically
pleasing smart versions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
However, we do have quite a few power strips with things like computer charging
bricks and TV's plugged in, which don't need to be powered up overnight. The
TECKIN WiFi Smart Plug works both with Alexa and Google Home (not tested as I
don't have a Google Home device). You can control the sockets either by using
Alexa, or via the app. The app also allows you to turn the sockets on and off
and depending on your Internet setup you can do this if you only have a mobile
connection. You can also set up schedules and timers for the plug.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So far they have been very reliable and easy to set up. My only concern is that
the Smart Life app does require quite a few permissions and wants to know your
location.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2Hmxd5Y"&gt;Amazon link.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-03-10-amazon-smart-plugs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 17:59:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Timelapse Photography Using a DSLR, GoPro or Osmo Pocket</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-16-timelapse-photography/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I recently bought a DJI Osmo, which has a built in Interval Timer mode, which
re-ignited my interest in making time lapse videos. The Osmo makes this very
easy: you just set the timer interval, which determines the interval at which the Osmo takes
a JPEG and the length of time you want it to continue taking pictures. At the
end of the elapsed time (you can interrupt it earlier if you wish) it combines
the individual JPEG files into an mp4 video. It also saves the individual JPEG
files, so you can process them separately.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Previously I have used a GoPro (built in interval timer), a RaspberryPi (uses
cron as an interval timer), or a DSLR with an external Interval Timer to make
time lapses. Interval timers are available for a variety of cameras and are
relatively cheap (around £13). The Amazon link shows the one I use with my
Canon DSLR. &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2SVkiyV"&gt;Amazon link to interval timer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You will also require some sort of stable mount for the camera. Traditionally
this would be a tripod. However, I like making time lapses in the mountains and
don't really want to lug 10kg of tripod for several hours up a mountain in
addition to all my camping gear. If the terrain is rocky you can usually find a
convenient rock or trig point which you can use to perch a mini tripod. If the
ground is grassy I have a lash up of various GoPro adaptors attached to a
walking pole, which I push into the ground.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Making a time lapse of a sunset or sunrise requires quite a lot of planning and
a lot of luck with the weather. First you need to work out what time the sun
rises and sets. Most smartphone weather apps will have this
information. Secondly you will need to find a location that provides an
unobstructed view of the horizon. Bear in mind that the sunrise and sunset will
move across the horizon between the two equinoxes according to the date.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next you need to decide on the time interval at which you want to take a
photograph. I have found around 5 seconds to work for me. It doesn't matter if
you take too many photographs, but it does if you don't take enough! I would
suggest that you start recording at least an hour before sunset. It's also
worth continuing to take photos for at least an hour after the official sunset
time. Once the sun has gone below the horizon you will often get an alpenglow
effect, which can last quite some time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You should now have an SD card with hundreds of images on it. There are a
number of methods of creating an mp4 file from the images. I use a combination
of ffmpeg and mencoder. I think these are available for most platforms, they
definitely work on Linux and Mac OS. Ffmpeg is the Swiss Army knife of video
processing tools. It's under constant development and the developer has been
known to change the syntax of the command line options at a whim.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is a link to "FFMPEG An Intermediate Guide/image sequence":
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/FFMPEG_An_Intermediate_Guide/image_sequence"&gt;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/FFMPEG_An_Intermediate_Guide/image_sequence&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I use ffmpeg to combine the individual jpegs into an mp4 video. Your jpegs will
almost certainly be numbered with a suffix that increases by one for each
successive photo, so you can automate the process using a script or batch file.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once you have created the mp4 you will probably find the mp4 file created from
several hundred jpeg images is only a few seconds long. You can use mencoder to
create a slow motion version of the mp4 video. Finally, you may want to add
some background music to your video. You can use ffmpeg to add an mp3 track
which adds the audio, but stops when it runs out of video to process.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
For full details about creating mp4 files from individual JPEGs, slowing down
the video and adding an audio track see my blog post at:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org14f916e" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org14f916e"&gt;Concatenating JPEG Files Into an mp4 File.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org14f916e"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tools required:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;mencoder&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;
sox
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If your JPEG file names end in a number, you can use the "-start&lt;sub&gt;number&lt;/sub&gt;"
command line option:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  ffmpeg -start_number n -i test_%d.jpg -vcodec mpeg4 test.mp4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
G0010024.JPG
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  ffmpeg  -start_number 10024 -i G00%d.JPG   -vcodec mpeg4 test.mp4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Note, this will work as long as the sequence is unbroken once it starts. If
there are gaps and you want all of the stills included, then renumbering may be
necessary to fill the gaps.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org3bd4cb1" class="outline-3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="org3bd4cb1"&gt;GoPro ffmpeg Command Line.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-3" id="text-org3bd4cb1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is the script I use with my GoPro. It creates a 1080p file from a JPEG. The %d is a placeholder for a number, so
files starting from G0017096.JPG will be concatenated to make the video.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   ffmpeg -f image2 -r 1 -start_number 17096 -i G00%d.JPG   -s hd1080 -vcodec libx264 timelapse_1080P.mp4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id="outline-container-org60e2a32" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org60e2a32"&gt;Using mencoder to Create a "Slow" Version of the Video.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org60e2a32"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This example slows the video down by 50% at 25 frames per second.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; mencoder -speed 0.5 -ofps 25 -ovc copy Flapse_25fps.mp4 -o slower.mp4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="outline-container-org938e085" class="outline-2"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="org938e085"&gt;Adding Background Music.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="outline-text-2" id="text-org938e085"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are several ways to do this. If your video is longer than the background
music track, you probably want the music to loop until it reaches the end of
the video.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I'd recommend sox and the -shortest option for ffmpeg as a solution.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; sox -i short_audio.mp3 looped_audio.mp3 repeat 1000 # adjust count as necessary
 ffmpeg -i input_video.mp4 -i looped_audio.mp3 -shortest output_video.mp4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The sox command will loop the input, and the ffmpeg command will use it for
the audio, but stop when it runs out of video to process.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
-i parameter is deprecated in sox. Is is properly to use -e ima-adpcm instead.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are several sources of free background music on the Internet. For
example:  &lt;a href="https://longzijun.wordpress.com/2010/05/28/free-background-music/"&gt;background music&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-16-timelapse-photography/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 16:52:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Manfrotto Mini Pixi Tripod</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-14-manfrotto-mini-pixi-tripod/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/manfrotto_tripod.jpg" class="rounded
float-left" alt="Manfrotto Pixi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/manfrotto_tripod.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have recently bought a Osmo Pocket and want to make some videos that require
the Osmo to be mounted on a tripod. I already have a Velbon full sized tripod, that
belonged to my father, which I could use. I want to use the Osmo on some
mountain walks and to record some climbing. In the past I have carted the
Velbon strapped to the outside of my rucksack, but the extra weight has put me
off taking it with me on a regular basis. I have also got a Gorilla Pod clone,
which is good on uneven ground, but isn't particularly stable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are lots of mini tripods available on Amazon, but I noticed the Manfrotto
Pixi was on sale for £12.50. Full sized Manfrotto tripods have a good
reputation, so I decided to purchase the Mini Pixi. The legs are non extendable
and have a small rubber pod at the ends of the feet that help to stop the
tripod sliding on slippy surfaces. When the legs are closed you can use the
tripod as a grip.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Like many other mini tripods there is a ball and socket joint that allows you
to tilt and pan the camera. To tilt and pan you press the small button and
rotate the head to the desired position than simply let the button go to lock
the head. This makes it much easier to adjust the position of the head
accurately unlike systems which require you to manually tighten a friction
joint.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried the tripod my Canon DSLR with a standard lens and it was stable, so it
should be OK with any compact camera or phone. It costs £19.50 on Amazon at the
moment, but I was lucky enough to pick it up in a flash sale for £12.70.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2IeCiiQ"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-14-manfrotto-mini-pixi-tripod/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:00:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Honor Play</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-01-28-honor-play/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/honor_play.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Honor Play"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/honor_play.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My Lenovo P2 has been an excellent phone for the last couple of years. Decent
performance and outstanding battery life. However, I am finding it's 32 GByte of
internal storage a bit limiting. It's stuck on Android 7.0 with a November 2017
security update and has been abandoned by Lenovo. I decided to have a look at
what was available for less than £300.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After looking at various reviews the Honor 8 with 6.5" screen seemed to fit my
requirements. However, it had a micro usb port, not USBC. I now have several
devices that have USBC ports and buying a new phone with micro USB connector
seemed a bit "Olde school". After a bit more research I discovered the Honor 8
Play. This is basically a souped up version of the Honor 8, supposedly aimed at
gamers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Specs. include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6.3-inch full view display LCD IPS (1080 x 2340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16MP+2MP dual AI camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3750mAH  battery supports 1.5 days of heavy usage and includes 9V/2A quick charge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirin 970 AI Chipset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64 GByte on board storage with micro/usb dual SIM capability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USBC connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
On Amazon it was priced at £240, well within my budget. Now I am not a gamer,
but I thought paying a bit extra for a phone that had better performance and
USBC was worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Initial setup was a bit unusual. Honor has their own Phone Clone app that did
an excellent job of transferring all my apps and data from the P2. The phone
has a Notch, that bothered me for all of about 5 minutes before I ignored
it. There is a fingerprint scanner on the back and face recognition works
really well, even when I am wearing my beanie and reading glasses.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Honor's UI seemed OK, but as a long time Nova user, I just restored my saved
settings from the P2. The phone is not officially water proof, but the only time this
has been a problem for me was back when I had a Nokia 5800 that was inside the
top pocket of my rucksack and the screen died either from moisture or the cold
in a snow storm. At full brightness you can see the screen OK in bright sun,
but I normally run it at about 20%. The screen aspect ratio makes it easy to
reach either edge of the screen, but as I never use the phone one handed that
doesn't matter to me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Speaker is OK, but I only use it for listening to phone calls. It does have
the dinosaur 3.5mm jack.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Huawei gives you an awful lot of settings to tinker with, but sometimes this
makes it difficult to find a particular setting buried deep in some menu.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The phone came with Anrdoid 8.0, but immediately updated to 9.0 with November
2018 security patches.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As it's meant to be a gaming phone, it came with several pre-installed games,
all of which I immediately deleted. There are a couple of other Honor apps that
can be deleted if you want to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Bluetooth connected to all my headphones and speakers without a problem. The
bluetooth version is 4.2 with AptX HD.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Main camera is 16 MP, f/2.2 with the front camera being 16 MP, f/2.0. Photos
are fine for me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Battery life - I had no problem getting through a day with more than 50%
available at bed time most days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2UNNhkU"&gt;https://amzn.to/2UNNhkU&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-01-28-honor-play/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 14:33:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Poundland Christmas lights Mods.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Plus how to make them run from a usb charger instead of batteries. You need a
couple of 10 ohm resistors and a soldering iron. I am definitely going to try
this. One of those "I did it because I could" projects.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="" height="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_ds5XFJvPs?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:44:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Free Photos</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
When we went to see our eldest daughter at Uni last weekend I noticed that she
had lots of postcard-sized photos on her noticeboard. Prints are "Free" up to
45 6x4 per month, or a total of 500 per year. Other sizes are available if you
pay. There is a delivery charge of £3.99 (ie not totally free), but it seems
reasonable for what you get. You can print directly from Google photos, or
photos on your phone. Quality looked OK to me, but I am not a pixel peeper.
&lt;a href="http://www.freeprints.co.uk"&gt;http://www.freeprints.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brother P Labeller</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have had a Brother P Touch label printer for years. I don't think that they
sell my model any longer and I expect you can find a cheaper equivalent to this
one. It's very simple to use and has a built-in cutter and gizmo to separate
the label from the backing tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I use it for labeling all sorts of things, such as files and storage
boxes. It's great for labeling wall warts. Most of us have drawers full of
rechargeable electronic items, which come with their own wall wart. If you
don't label the plug it can be almost impossible to work out which plug you
should use to power/recharge a particular bit of electronics.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2Cf2IuE"&gt;Amazon link.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:09:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Service Charges in Restaurants</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Service Charges in Restaurants.  If I go to a restaurant, rather than a self
service cafe, I can't avoid "Service". It's a non optional part of the
experience. As such the price should be built into the price of the meal. If I
get crap service, I simply won't go back to the same place again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don't think any other part of the economy has such a strange idea of selling
you something that includes a service element. If I take my car into the garage
I don't expect to pay an extra 10% because the mechanic did their job properly.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:08:16 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>