<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ian's Mutterings. (Posts about whateverworks)</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://ianbarton.net/categories/whateverworks.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:ian@ianbarton.net"&gt;Ian Barton.&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 12:53:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Manfrotto Mini Pixi Tripod</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-14-manfrotto-mini-pixi-tripod/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/manfrotto_tripod.jpg" class="rounded
float-left" alt="Manfrotto Pixi"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/manfrotto_tripod.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I have recently bought a Osmo Pocket and want to make some videos that require
the Osmo to be mounted on a tripod. I already have a Velbon full sized tripod, that
belonged to my father, which I could use. I want to use the Osmo on some
mountain walks and to record some climbing. In the past I have carted the
Velbon strapped to the outside of my rucksack, but the extra weight has put me
off taking it with me on a regular basis. I have also got a Gorilla Pod clone,
which is good on uneven ground, but isn't particularly stable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are lots of mini tripods available on Amazon, but I noticed the Manfrotto
Pixi was on sale for £12.50. Full sized Manfrotto tripods have a good
reputation, so I decided to purchase the Mini Pixi. The legs are non extendable
and have a small rubber pod at the ends of the feet that help to stop the
tripod sliding on slippy surfaces. When the legs are closed you can use the
tripod as a grip.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Like many other mini tripods there is a ball and socket joint that allows you
to tilt and pan the camera. To tilt and pan you press the small button and
rotate the head to the desired position than simply let the button go to lock
the head. This makes it much easier to adjust the position of the head
accurately unlike systems which require you to manually tighten a friction
joint.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I tried the tripod my Canon DSLR with a standard lens and it was stable, so it
should be OK with any compact camera or phone. It costs £19.50 on Amazon at the
moment, but I was lucky enough to pick it up in a flash sale for £12.70.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2IeCiiQ"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-02-14-manfrotto-mini-pixi-tripod/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 11:00:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Honor Play</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-01-28-honor-play/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/honor_play.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Honor Play"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/honor_play.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My Lenovo P2 has been an excellent phone for the last couple of years. Decent
performance and outstanding battery life. However, I am finding it's 32 GByte of
internal storage a bit limiting. It's stuck on Android 7.0 with a November 2017
security update and has been abandoned by Lenovo. I decided to have a look at
what was available for less than £300.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After looking at various reviews the Honor 8 with 6.5" screen seemed to fit my
requirements. However, it had a micro usb port, not USBC. I now have several
devices that have USBC ports and buying a new phone with micro USB connector
seemed a bit "Olde school". After a bit more research I discovered the Honor 8
Play. This is basically a souped up version of the Honor 8, supposedly aimed at
gamers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Specs. include:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class="org-ul"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6.3-inch full view display LCD IPS (1080 x 2340)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16MP+2MP dual AI camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3750mAH  battery supports 1.5 days of heavy usage and includes 9V/2A quick charge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirin 970 AI Chipset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64 GByte on board storage with micro/usb dual SIM capability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USBC connector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
On Amazon it was priced at £240, well within my budget. Now I am not a gamer,
but I thought paying a bit extra for a phone that had better performance and
USBC was worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Initial setup was a bit unusual. Honor has their own Phone Clone app that did
an excellent job of transferring all my apps and data from the P2. The phone
has a Notch, that bothered me for all of about 5 minutes before I ignored
it. There is a fingerprint scanner on the back and face recognition works
really well, even when I am wearing my beanie and reading glasses.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Honor's UI seemed OK, but as a long time Nova user, I just restored my saved
settings from the P2. The phone is not officially water proof, but the only time this
has been a problem for me was back when I had a Nokia 5800 that was inside the
top pocket of my rucksack and the screen died either from moisture or the cold
in a snow storm. At full brightness you can see the screen OK in bright sun,
but I normally run it at about 20%. The screen aspect ratio makes it easy to
reach either edge of the screen, but as I never use the phone one handed that
doesn't matter to me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Speaker is OK, but I only use it for listening to phone calls. It does have
the dinosaur 3.5mm jack.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Huawei gives you an awful lot of settings to tinker with, but sometimes this
makes it difficult to find a particular setting buried deep in some menu.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The phone came with Anrdoid 8.0, but immediately updated to 9.0 with November
2018 security patches.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As it's meant to be a gaming phone, it came with several pre-installed games,
all of which I immediately deleted. There are a couple of other Honor apps that
can be deleted if you want to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Bluetooth connected to all my headphones and speakers without a problem. The
bluetooth version is 4.2 with AptX HD.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Main camera is 16 MP, f/2.2 with the front camera being 16 MP, f/2.0. Photos
are fine for me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Battery life - I had no problem getting through a day with more than 50%
available at bed time most days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2UNNhkU"&gt;https://amzn.to/2UNNhkU&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2019-01-28-honor-play/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 14:33:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Poundland Christmas lights Mods.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Plus how to make them run from a usb charger instead of batteries. You need a
couple of 10 ohm resistors and a soldering iron. I am definitely going to try
this. One of those "I did it because I could" projects.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe width="" height="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_ds5XFJvPs?rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&amp;amp;wmode=transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-poundland-christmas-lights-mods/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:44:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Free Photos</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
When we went to see our eldest daughter at Uni last weekend I noticed that she
had lots of postcard-sized photos on her noticeboard. Prints are "Free" up to
45 6x4 per month, or a total of 500 per year. Other sizes are available if you
pay. There is a delivery charge of £3.99 (ie not totally free), but it seems
reasonable for what you get. You can print directly from Google photos, or
photos on your phone. Quality looked OK to me, but I am not a pixel peeper.
&lt;a href="http://www.freeprints.co.uk"&gt;http://www.freeprints.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-21-free-photo-prints/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 17:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brother P Labeller</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
I have had a Brother P Touch label printer for years. I don't think that they
sell my model any longer and I expect you can find a cheaper equivalent to this
one. It's very simple to use and has a built-in cutter and gizmo to separate
the label from the backing tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I use it for labeling all sorts of things, such as files and storage
boxes. It's great for labeling wall warts. Most of us have drawers full of
rechargeable electronic items, which come with their own wall wart. If you
don't label the plug it can be almost impossible to work out which plug you
should use to power/recharge a particular bit of electronics.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2Cf2IuE"&gt;Amazon link.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-brother-p-labeller/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:09:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Service Charges in Restaurants</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Service Charges in Restaurants.  If I go to a restaurant, rather than a self
service cafe, I can't avoid "Service". It's a non optional part of the
experience. As such the price should be built into the price of the meal. If I
get crap service, I simply won't go back to the same place again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don't think any other part of the economy has such a strange idea of selling
you something that includes a service element. If I take my car into the garage
I don't expect to pay an extra 10% because the mechanic did their job properly.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-service-charges-in-restaurants/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:08:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Duronic Electric Hub</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-duronic-electric-hub/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/duronic_hob.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Thermos"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/duronic_hob.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A recent problem with our Aga means that we are without heating in the kitchen,
clothes dryer, hot water and the ability to cook anything except by using the
microwave. It will probably be out of action for a week or so while I run some
new copper pipe and move the control box.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The Duronic Electric Hob has two different sized rings and seems reliable so
far. It's easy to clean and powerful enough to heat things rapidly. I think
it's pasta with everything until the Aga is fixed:)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2ABA5rz"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-duronic-electric-hub/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:06:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Citibikes Vienna</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-citibikes-vienna/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
A few years ago I tried to hire a couple of Boris Bikes in London with my
son. Despite help from an Official Assistant, we were unable to unlock two
bikes at once. So Boris you owe me £15, which with late payment charges and
interest comes to just over £10,000.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Citibikes in Vienna is much better! There are various apps which show you the
location of all the docking stations and the number of bikes available at each
one. You can do most of the preliminary registration stuff on the
website. However, the final step of registering your debit card requires you to
use one of the card readers at a bike station. Note for Monzo users, just tell
the machine it's a credit card when registering.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fees are very reasonable. The first hour is free and the second costs
1EU. Vienna is pancake flat with lots of cycle lanes, so even occasional
cyclists should be fine cycling around easy and safe.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
However, the bikes are really heavy. They would probably survive a direct hit
from an anti-tank missile. There is a single front brake, but the main braking
is activated by back pedaling. If you are used to aligning your pedals when you
mount the bike by sticking your foot under a pedal and back pedalling to get
the pedal in the correct position, you can't do this on a Citibike.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There are three gears. However, the weight of the bike means that even on
slight inclines you have to push hard in the lowest gear.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If you are a regular cyclist you will find the weight and braking system very
annoying. On my 6.5k ride I averaged about 16kph. On a similar route with my
normal road bike this would have been about 35kph.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In conclusion good bike for short rides (10-15 minutes) at a very reasonable
price.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.citybikewien.at/en/"&gt;https://www.citybikewien.at/en/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-citibikes-vienna/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:05:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Self Assembly Flat Pack Furniture</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-self-assembly-flat-pack-furniture/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
Self Assembly Furniture.  +Ted Salmon You need to hire my 17 year old
daughter:) She is an absolute wizard. Wardrobes, desks, cupboards, etc. Give
her a few tools and come back in a couple of hours to view the finished
product. For some weird reason she enjoys doing it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-self-assembly-flat-pack-furniture/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:03:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lint and Fluff Roller.</title><link>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-lint-and-fluff-roller/</link><dc:creator>Ian Barton.</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://ianbarton.net/images/lint_roller.jpg" class="rounded float-left" alt="Thermos"&gt;&lt;img src="https://ianbarton.net/images/lint_roller.thumbnail.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In a house full of cats and a dog, clothes quickly get covered with various cat
and dog hairs. Lazy people like me just ignore them. However, the female
members of the household are much fussier :) These lint rollers are very
effective at getting off animal hairs from your clothes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
They come with a roll of "sticky tape" in perforated sections. You tear off a
section and wrap it around the roller. The run the roller over your clothes and
the hairs will automagically stick to it. If you stick a plastic bag over the
roller when you have finished, you can get multiple uses from each sticky tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2TA3No6"&gt;
Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>whateverworks</category><guid>https://ianbarton.net/posts/2018-11-15-lint-and-fluff-roller/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:02:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>